{"tossups": [{"question": "One leader of this state, John McKinly, was captured in bed by the British. The Swedish settlement of Fort Christina is located in this state. This state disputed a small tract known as the Wedge with its northern neighbor until 1921. Until it gained an independent legislature in 1701, it was known as the\u201cThree Lower Counties.\u201d This state\u2019s northern border is an arc centered on the courthouse in New Castle, the Twelve-Mile Circle, and its western border is the Mason-Dixon line. For ten points, name this small Mid-Atlantic state where an 1861 vote against secession from the Union was taken in Dover.", "answer": "<b> Delaware</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A videotape showing this man with Thomas Youk ends with this man challenging the authorities to convict him. Shortly after this man worked with Janet Adkins, the state of Michigan revoked his license. This man employed the use of the Mercitron and the Thanatron to deliver, respectively, carbon monoxide or an IV drip of lethal medicine. For ten points, name this doctor who, in 1999, was convicted of murder and served eight years in prison for his role in over one hundred physician-assisted suicides.", "answer": "Dr. Jack<b> Kevorkian</b> (prompt on Dr. Death)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "This composer wrote the piece \u201cA new song we raise\u201d in response to the execution of Johann Esch and Heinrich Voes. J.S. Bach wrote a set of canonic variations on his Christmas piece \u201cVom himmel hoch.\u201d Another of his hymns was quoted in the finale of Felix Mendelssohn\u2019s fifth symphony, written for the 300th anniversary of the Augsburg Confession. \u201cA Mighty Fortress is Our God\u201d was written by, for ten points, what German whose hymns and other religious writings, including the Ninety-Five Theses, helped initiate the Protestant Reformation?", "answer": "Martin<b> Luther</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This organization defended its unorthodox contractual procedure in a court case against Iain Fraser. It is currently lead by Don Garber and unofficially runs the Cascadia Cup. Its first ever match was contested between San Jose Clash and DCU at Spartan Stadium, and it grew out of the failed NASL. This league\u2019s Designated Player rule has allowed David Villa, Kaka, and other imports to join it, as its attractiveness to foreigners grew following David Beckham\u2019s transfer to the LA Galaxy. For ten points, name this modern American soccer league.", "answer": "<b> Major League Soccer</b> (or<b> MLS</b>)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "As part of this policy, Raycom Sports planned a football game between USC and Illinois in Dynamo Stadium. This policy led to the success of the Phosphorite War. The anti-Stalinist novel<em> Children of the</em> <em>Arbat</em> was allowed to be published under this system. Along with a policy translated as \u201crestructuring,\u201dthis policy helped lead to the independence of many constituent republics of the Eastern Bloc. For ten points, name this policy under Mikhail Gorbachev that advocated for greater freedom of speech and government transparency and comes from the Russian word for \u201copenness.\u201d", "answer": "<b> glasnost</b> (prompt on \u201copenness\u201d before read)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "The day before 2004 elections on this island, Annette Lu and Chen Shui-bian were shot. After easier negotiations for part of Liaodong and the Penghu Islands, China begrudgingly granted Japan control of this island in the 1895 Treaty of Shimonoseki. Lee Teng-hui once served as president of a government that rules this island, where Tsai Ing-wen was elected president in 2016.. For ten points, name this island, formerly known as Formosa, that, since 1949, has been home to the government of the People\u2019s Republic of China.", "answer": "<b> Taiwan</b> (accept<b> Formosa</b> before mentioned; do not accept Republic of China)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "Due to his cruelty, this man was replaced by Francisco de Bobadilla in a position that he had been granted by the Capitulations of Santa Fe. This man outlined what he was owed by the Spanish Crown in the<em> Book of Privileges</em>. This man forced the Taino to pay him tribute after colonizing their home, which was later named Hispaniola. For ten points, name this Italian explorer whose voyages, funded by Ferdinand and Isabella, led to Spanish colonization in the New World.", "answer": "Christopher<b> Columbus</b> (or Cristobal<b> Colon</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "The loser of this battle made the mistake of deploying Richard Caswell\u2019s militia against his enemy\u2019s strongest flank. It was preceded by the battle of Waxhaws. Johann de Kalb was killed during this battle, which was prompted by Lord Rawdon\u2019s calls for aid. This battle was decided when the North Carolina and Delaware regiments were broken by Tarleton\u2019s Legion. This victory for Charles Cornwallis led colonial leadership to appoint Nathanael Greene as commander in the South. For ten points, name this British victory in the Carolinas that destroyed the reputation of Horatio Gates.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Camden</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Two answers required. Captain Polin led a diplomatic mission headed by the flagship Reale from one of these countries to the other. In a joint operation, these two countries successfully besieged the city of Nice during the Italian War of 1542-46. Thousands of soldiers of the losing side were executed in the aftermath of the 1799 Siege of Jaffa between these two countries. For ten points, name these two countries that formed an \u201cunholy alliance\u201d based on their mutual hatred of the Habsburgs and were led by Francis I and Suleiman the Magnificent.", "answer": "<b> France</b> and the<b> Ottoman</b> Empire (accept<b> Valois</b> dynasty for France)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This thinker wrote that \u201cour aversions and judgments are not, by any means, primarily rational in character\u201d in reference to attitudes to superficial features, like face shape and race. This figure studied how a tribe seemed to shift from patrilineal to matrilineal society; that Vancouver-area tribe was the Kwakiutl. This scholar\u2019s \u201cfour field\u201d approach included linguistic and archaeological research and was taught to students like Alfred Kroeber, Ruth Benedict, and Margaret Mead. For ten points, name this American thinker, the founder of Columbia University\u2019s revolutionary anthropology school and author of <em>The Mind of Primitive Man</em>.", "answer": "Franz<b> Boas</b>", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Anthropology"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "William Wade Dudley was accused of bribing electoral voters into selecting this man in the Blocks of Five Scandal. This President dealt with the crisis caused by the killing of two sailors from the USS <em>Baltimore</em>. Levi Morton served as Vice President under this man, who signed the McKinley Tariff and Sherman Antitrust Act. The 51st Congress, nicknamed the Billion Dollar Congress, served alongside, for ten points, what U.S. President who was succeeded and preceded in office by Grover Cleveland?", "answer": "<b> B</b>enjamin<b> Harrison</b> (prompt on Harrison)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This conflict opened with the battle of Pungdo, in which mutineers prevented T.R. Galsworthy from surrendering to the Naniwa. The public display of Kim Ok-gyun\u2019s dismembered body helped prompt this conflict. The Kowshing sunk in this conflict that was accelerated by one side\u2019s dependence on soy bean imports. The Triple Intervention occurred in this conflict, which opened with a dispute regarding the Donghak Peasant Rebellion and ended with the 1895 Treaty of Shimonoseki. For ten points, name this conflict between China and Japan.", "answer": "First<b> Sino-Japanese</b> War", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This work was appended by the essay \u201cGeneral Scholium,\u201d in which its author claimed that he did not pretend to know things he didn\u2019t know, a concept now called hypotheses non fingo. This work drew extensively on the observations of John Flamsteed, which was used to study Kepler\u2019s laws. The three-body problem was explored in this work, which attempts to explain the motion of the Moon under the gravity of the Earth and the Sun. Its insights include a law that states that force equals mass times acceleration. For ten points, name this work that states the law of gravitation and the laws of motion, written by Isaac Newton.", "answer": "Philosophiae Naturalis<b> Principia</b> Mathematica", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "One of these events, known as<em> qatl-e-aam</em>, started when a leader rode into the Chandi Chowk market and unsheathed his sword. Another of these events was preceded by a battle in which flaming camels were used to combat war elephants and resulted in a pyramid made of 80,000 human skulls. Nadir Shah led one of these events, which was preceded by the Battle of Karnal, and that one of these events caused the capture of the Kooh-i-Noor diamond and the Peacock Throne. For ten points, name these events in which an invading force looted the final Mughal capital.", "answer": "<b> sacks</b> of<b> Delhi</b> (or<b> sacks</b> of<b> Shahjahanabad</b>; accept equivalents for sack)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "The 10th century Denkard compendium lists customs of this religion. Invocations to Apas and Zam, or water and earth, are collected in this religion\u2019s Vendidad. This religion holds that the forces of asha and druj work against each other and that souls must cross the Chinvat Bridge for judgment. The legendary king Vishtaspa was the first adherent of this religion, whose worshipers gather in fire temples. The Avesta is the holy scripture of, for ten points, what Iranian religion whose Avesta collects the Gathas, the sayings of its founder, Zarathustra?", "answer": "<b> Zoroastrian</b>ism", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {}, {"question": "<b>The first member of this group forbade gold and silver statues to be made of him; that man\u2019s authority diminished when Casparius Aelianus demanded that he hand over the murderers of his predecessor. Edward Gibbon stated that this group\u2019s rule was \u201cthe most (+) happy and prosperous\u201d period in world history. This group\u2019s name was coined by Niccolo Machiavelli, who suggested that this group was successful because they were all (*) </b>adopted and did not inherit their position. For ten points, name this group of Roman rulers whose rule from 96 to 180 CE was marked by peace and prosperity.", "answer": "<b> Five Good Emperors</b> (prompt on Nerva-Antonine dynasty)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "<b>This leader planned Operation Lal Dora, which was a proposed invasion of Mauritius. This leader\u2019s passing of the 26th amendment led to the abolition of the Privy Purse. One slogan used by this leader called to \u201cgarib hatao,\u201d or \u201cabolish poverty.\u201d The (+) Allahabad High Court declared this leader\u2019s election null and void due to malpractice, which led to a period of rule by decree known as The (*) </b> Emergency. After ordering Operation Blue Star, this leader was assassinated by her Sikh Bodyguards. For ten points, name this daughter of Jawaharlal Nehru who served as Prime Minister of India.", "answer": "<b> I</b>ndira<b> Gandhi</b> (prompt on Gandhi)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man did not personally go on a voyage he organized that installed Mana Vikraman as king of Calicut. This man\u2019s political interventions included capturing the usurper (+) Sekandar of Semudera and capturing King Alagonakkara of Kotte. On his first voyage, this man captured the pirate Chen Zuyi. On his fifth voyage, this man explored the (*)</b> Arabian coast from Hormuz to Aden before sailing as far south as Mombasa and bringing a giraffe to the Yongle Emperor. For ten points, name this admiral who organized seven voyages for the Ming Dynasty.", "answer": "<b> Zheng He</b> (accept<b> Ma Sanbao</b> or<b> Ma He</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>George Pearkes described a contingency for this action as a \u201cfantastic desperate plan\u201dwhich \u201cjust might have worked.\u201d That plan, developed by James Brown, called for the</b> <b>immediate seizure of the Great Falls at the occurrence of this event. (+)</b> <b>Defense Scheme</b> <b>No. 1 was designed to prevent this action which was called for in War Plan Crimson. In planning for this action, one government noted that Route 99 \u201cis the best practicable route to (*)</b> Vancouver.\u201d For ten points, name this hypothetical action in which American forces would have attempted to seize cities like Ottawa.", "answer": "U.S.<b> invasion of Canada</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>In March 2016, this organization noted that \u201cTariq Ramadan is never going to grab a Kalashnikov\u201d in an editorial that laments the retreat of secularism. That editorial blamed</b> <b>bakers who refuse to sell ham for their role in the (+)</b> <b>Brussels attacks, which this</b> <b>organization called \u201cthe visible part of a very large iceberg.\u201d G\u00b4erard Biard [bee-arhd] is the (*) </b> editor-in-chief of this organization, for which Jean Cabut [zhan ka-boo] and St\u00b4ephane Charbonnier [steff-ahn sharb-ohn-ee-ay] worked as cartoonists until a January 2015 attack. The editorial \u201cHow did we end up here?\u201d was published by, for ten points, what satirical French newspaper?", "answer": "<b> Charlie Hebdo</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "<b>A political cartoon made in response to this speech shows a red-caped anarchy behind a man wielding stolen regalia. Its speaker noted that \u201cWe come to speak for this broader class of businessman\u201d as \u201cthe individual is but an (+) atom,\u201d and cried \u201cWe beg no longer, we entreat no more...We defy them!\u201d This speech advocated a platform that included a (*) </b>16-to-1 exchange ratio, comparing the status quo to a \u201ccrown of thorns\u201d. For ten points, name this speech that sealed the 1896 Democratic nomination for William Jennings Bryan, who demanded that mankind not be \u201ccrucified\u201d on the title object.", "answer": "<b> Cross of Gold</b> speech", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This group largely took inspiration from Carlos Marighella\u2019s Minimanual of the Urban Guerilla. Members of this group committed suicide during \u201cdeath night\u201d while being held in Stammheim Prison. The first incarnation of this group is referred to as the (+) Baader-Meinhof Gang, and it was responsible for the deaths of Jurgen Ponto and Hanns Schleyer during the (*) </b> 1977 German Autumn. For ten points, name this West German left-wing terrorist group that operated during the 1970s.", "answer": "<b> R</b>ed<b> A</b>rmy<b> F</b>action (or<b> R</b>ote<b> A</b>rmee<b> F</b>raktion; prompt on Baader-Meinhof Gang before it is read)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Helmand Province in the Golden Crescent produces over half of the world\u2019s supply</b> <b>of this commodity. The seizure of the</b><em><b> Arrow</b></em><b> on charges of suspected (+)</b> <b>piracy in</b> <b>Canton led to a war named for this commodity, which was destroyed by the crateful</b> <b>by Lin Zexu. The Treaty of (*)</b> Nanking ended a conflict over, for ten points, what addictive drug, popularly consumed in \u201cdens\u201d and derived from the poppy plant, that names a series of 19th century wars between Great Britain and China?", "answer": "<b> opium</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}